Henrique Freire Ponce Leon

Administrative Assistant

Eligeble to work full time (Stamp 4)

henriqueponceleon@gmail.com

+353 85 128 1835

https://www.linkedin.com/in/henrique-freire-ponce-leon-90309b138

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I have been engaged in environmental management at Renault of Brazil, part of the Renault group, since 2017 until 2022. I am a self-motivated, proactive and organized professional. During my 5 years in a multinational, I became able to work with my own initiative, develop communication skills, good organization and the ability to work with defined standard procedures. I have also worked as a receptionist, bartender/barista and kitchen assistant, so I can easily work in a team and in a fast-paced environment as well. I am a focused professional with willingness to learn more.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Environmental area, Administration, Customers service, Logistic and Management.

HIGHLIGHTS AND KEY SKILLS

- Communication skills: Good listener, clear, confident and respectful communicator.
- Languages: Portuguese native speaker, fluent in English.
- Management: Data control skills, operational planning, logistical management, financial management.
- Audit: Environmental audit, financial and data's audit, analytical capabilities.
- Collaboration: Ability to work in a team and share ideas.
- IT Skills: Excellent working knowledge of all Microsoft Office package.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Receptionist - Dublin Airport Lounge (Compass Group) - Dublin/IE

January 2023 - Present

Experiences acquired as Receptionist at Dublin Airport Lounge:

- Responsible for checking in all customers according to the type of registration on DAA System.
- Responsible for closing reception, sending all daily results files (excel base).
- Customer support with flight information, gates and more.
- Barista activities.
- Bartender activities.
- Make flight announcements.
- Training new staffs, showing them how to do reception activities.

Kitchen Assistant - Look Mam No Hands Cafe - Dublin/IE

July 2022 - January 2023

Experiences acquired as Kitchen Assistant at Look Mam No Hands Cafe:

- Support chefs in managing preparation to achieve precise plating and presentation
- Responsible for food preparation in the morning shift, such as frying sausages, pudding, hash browns and premaking veggies.
- Responsible for receiving kitchen products from suppliers and organise them in stock.
- Responsible for checking all the refrigerators to make sure that have labels updated.
- Responsible for closing kitchen time by cleaning.
- Training new staffs, showing them how to prepare the food and present it.
- Trusted with establishment key.

Administrative Assistant – Groupe Renault – Curitiba/BR

April 2017 - May 2022

Experiences acquired as Administrative Assistant at Renault of Brazil:

- Project management with financial and environmental performance.
- Waste Management.
- Annual waste inventory.
- Cargo scheduling.

- Approval of monthly waste contracts.
- Compliance with legal waste requirements.
- Elaboration of PGRS (Waste management plan).
- Waste movements in MTR systems (SINIR, CADEF, others).
- Waste KPI's management.
- Circular Economy Pilot.
- Hoster of Scrap Resales Atelier at Monozukuri Brazil.
- Internal audit (inspection of chemical products, waste disposal).
- Analysis of MSDS according to GHS.
- Actions in Internal Communication on the Environment.
- Participation in the Renault of Brazil Sustainability Report.
- Support ISO 14001 requirements.
- Compliance and application of internal procedures.

Other Results achieved as an Environment team:

- Zero Landfill Plant.
- Maintenance of ISO 14001 Certification.
- Finalist at the TDC Renault 2017 Award recognizing the Group's best projects in the world.
- Financial saving [in millions of reais (BRL coin)] and reduction in waste disposal (in thousands of tons).
- Benchmarking in reuse of industrial logistical waste.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

- Leaving Certificate (High School) Curso e Colegio Acesso Curitiba/BR (2014-2016)
- Business Conduct Certificate Compass Group Dublin/IE (2023)
- Health and Safety Certificate Compass Group Dublin/IE (2023)
- PCI Compliance Certificate Compass Group Dublin/IE (2023)
- Code of Business Conduct Certificate Compass Group Dublin/IE (2023)

Recommendation Letter for Employment

Date: May 16th, 2022

To Whom This May Concern,

My name is Guilherme Setsuo Baba and I am pleased to offer my recommendation of Henrique Leon.

During my relationship with Henrique Leon over the last years, I have experienced a highly motivated, hard-working individual who consistently arrives on time and shows great dedication towards his professional duties.

Leon has experience in several roles in the Environment Department of Renault such as Waste management, Environmental Monitoring Plans, KPI management among others. All the challenges he faced were successfully accomplished, due to his strong sense of commitment and fast learning abilities.

I strongly believe that Henrique Leon will be a great addition to your company and will exceed expectations in his role.

Please do not hesitate to contact me if you should require any additional information.

Sincerely,

Guilherme Setsuo Babá

Date May 16th, 2022

HSEE General Manager – LATAM Cluster

GROUPE RENAULT

+55 41 99283 1972

guilherme.baba@renault.com

